{
  "year2Ques": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "We can do all these things with the computer EXCEPT",
      "options": ["washing", "browsing", "playing games", "sending messages"],
      "answer": "washing"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "___is known as the brain box of the computer",
      "options": ["monitor", "CPU", "keyboard", "mouse"],
      "answer": "CPU"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Which of these is a way of caring for the computer",
      "options": ["expose it to dust", "keep it in a hot room", "if it stops working, call a computer engineer", "pour water on it"],
      "answer": "if it stops working, call a computer engineer"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "The ____is an output device, it is an electronic device that looks like a television",
      "options": ["mouse", "CPU", "printer", "monitor"],
      "answer": "monitor"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "__is flat and has the shape of a rectangle",
      "options": ["mouse", "keyboard", "cable", "software"],
      "answer": "keyboard"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "What part of the computer is used for pointing and selecting objects on the computer?",
      "options": ["keyboard", "speaker", "printer", "mouse"],
      "answer": "mouse"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "What device makes noise while typing?",
      "options": ["typewriter", "monitor", "CPU", "printer"],
      "answer": "typewriter"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "The part of a computer system that prints work on paper is called",
      "options": ["mouse", "monitor", "printer", "buttons"],
      "answer": "printer"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "In computing, UPS means",
      "options": ["undefeated personal service", "uninterrupted power supply", "unshakable power system", "unimportant power supply"],
      "answer": "uninterrupted power supply"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "In computing, the trash also has other names like __&__",
      "options": ["dustbin & recycle bin", "power & paper", "light & laser", "all of the above"],
      "answer": "dustbin & recycle bin"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "__is a machine which quickly copies documents onto papers by photographing them",
      "options": ["photocopier", "monitor", "mouse", "machine"],
      "answer": "photocopier"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Which of these is not a part of an extension box",
      "options": ["photocopier", "switchers", "sockets", "extension cord"],
      "answer": "photocopier"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "____is the action performed by an air conditioner",
      "options": ["printing", "photocopying", "typing", "air conditioning"],
      "answer": "air conditioning"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "___invented the air conditioner",
      "options": ["Carl Benz", "Charles Babbage", "Willis Carrier", "Abraham Lincoln"],
      "answer": "Willis Carrier"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "An electronic device that accepts data, processes data and brings it out as information is called",
      "options": ["sound machine", "computer", "mouse", "photography"],
      "answer": "computer"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "One of these is not an ICT device",
      "options": ["laptops", "computer", "smartphones", "water bottle"],
      "answer": "water bottle"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "We can care for ICT devices by",
      "options": ["avoid placing heavy objects on top of computers and other devices", "mishandling the devices", "washing them with soap and water", "heating them up"],
      "answer": "avoid placing heavy objects on top of computers and other devices"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "Which of the following is a part of a smartphone?",
      "options": ["keypad", "speaker", "battery", "all of the above"],
      "answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "What is the full meaning of ICT?",
      "options": ["international connection technical", "information and communication technology", "independence country campaign", "none of the above"],
      "answer": "information and communication technology"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "___ is a machine or device for cutting or trimming sheets of paper to required dimensions.",
      "options": ["paper cutter", "computer", "typewriter", "pumping machine"],
      "answer": "paper cutter"
    }
  ]
}